Laszlo Treszkai

Berlin-based, German resident · laszlo.tre@icloud.com · +49 152 3135 6006 · www.treszkai.com

14 years of experience with both Python and the Linux shell.

4 years of industry experience with the design, implementation, and evaluation of ML algorithms. Math-first understanding of Bayesian statistics and machine learning, incl. deep learning.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Power App Factory GmbH Backend Developer

July 2024 - Nov 2024

- Improved a data visualization feature across 3 microservices while increasing speed and simplifying code.
- Developed features end-to-end, covering requirements management, UI design, database schema modifications, implementing the feature and API changes, and testing.
- Introduced more Pythonic expressions throughout the codebase.
- Using Python, asyncio, SQLAlchemy, Redis, Pandas, GitLab CI, Flask.

Finmatics GmbH Backend & ML Engineer

Oct 2019 - May 2023

- Prevented downtime by developing robust database migrations for PostgreSQL to update data and schema.
- Analyzed and optimized slow SQL database queries.
- Used a NoSQL key-value cache (Redis) to implement locks and cache frequently retrieved data.
- Improved throughput through implementing parallelizable asynchronous task pipelines with Celery.
- Simplified code and increased speed with large-scale refactorings during feature development.
- Improved prediction accuracy (#1 problem of our customers) with ML to extract information from invoices, and introduced an evaluation system to test model accuracy to ensure that changes improve our KPIs.
- Using Python, PostgreSQL, Redis, NumPy, PyTorch, PyTorch Geometric, Pandas, Django, Docker, Celery.

Sclable Business Solutions GmbH Al Research Engineer

Nov 2018 - Mar 2019

- Reduced our client's engineering costs with a custom-made Bayesian recommendation system.
- Used Python, Tornado, PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy, Pandas, NumPy, SciPy, unittest, OpenCV.

TTControl GmbH Embedded Software Engineer

Apr 2014 - Mar 2016

- Worked on the company's most complex safety-critical electronic control unit at the time (HY-TTC 500)
- Developed core software features in C language and assembly for our ECU, such as EEPROM handling.
- Created testing tools and test cases in Python.
- Led successful certification discussions with the TÜV and coordinated software testing with off-site engineers.

Robert Bosch Kft. Test Software Developer Intern

Aug 2010 – Dec 2010

• Reduced the costs of system tests fivefold by implement a proprietary network protocol stack in Python.

EDUCATION

MSc: Artificial Intelligence

2017 - 2018

University of Edinburgh, United Kingdom

(with distinction)

- · Courses in probabilistic modelling, ML, deep learning, decision making, and natural language processing.
- Master's thesis: Likelihood-based Planning with Loops, presented at ICAPS.

BSc and **MSc**: Electrical Engineering (Embedded Information Systems)

2007 - 2013

Budapest University of Technology and Economics, Hungary

(degree: Excellent)

Laszlo Treszkai

PUBLICATIONS

PUBLICATIONS	
A Correctness Result for Synthesizing Plans With Loops in Stochastic Domains	2020
• First author of a paper on automated planning, with Vaishak Belle. (Int. J. of Approximate Reasoning)	
Crystal Clear Electronics C Chapter 16: The timer module	2018
 Authored a book chapter aimed at high school students on embedded hardware and software design 	١.
www.treszkai.com ♂ (Posts about programming, mathematics, Al.) 2018	– ongoing
Evaluation of function calls in Haskell . Paper summary: Inverse RL . Posterior sampling with MC	CMC 🗷
FURTHER PROJECTS	
The effects of daylight savings time adjustment on the incidence rate of acute myocardial infarcti	ion 🗹
Reinterpreting statistical significance with Bayesian methods • Estimate the increase in heart attacks after losing an hour of sleep, with well-defined credible intervals. • Fit a hierarchical statistical model on incidence counts using probabilistic programming with <i>PyStan</i> .	2019
BEST Python package: Bayesian Estimation Supersedes the t-test Main author of the best Python package, to serve as a Bayesian drop-in replacement for t-tests • Fit t-distributions on one-dimensional data with PyMC3, and plot posteriors with Matplotlib.	2019
Estimating the uncertainty of deep neural networks • Experiments with calibration methods, such as deep ensembles or test-time dropout. (Using Keras.)	2018
Literature Review: Noise-contrastive estimation and related methods Comparing generative adversarial networks (GANs) and their predecessor, noise-contrastive estimation	2017 n.
BME Formula Racing Team 20. Group Leader of Low Voltage Electronics (FREC-003 race car), Hardware+Firmware Engineer (FRC- • Designed the low voltage system of 9 electronic control units and 30 sensors in a Formula Student of • Lead a group of 7 students (mechanical and electrical engineers) to design and manufacture this system. • Team was awarded Engineering Design 1st place , Energy Efficiency 1st place at the international F	car. em.

learn was awarded Engineering Design 1st place G, Energy Efficiency 1st place G at the international FSH 2013.